Jacob Hocker

14220 Park Row, Houston, Texas 77084 USA | 713-292-6730 | jacobdouglas06@gmail.com Github | Medium Blog | Linked In | Portfolio

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER

Experience using front end and back end technologies such as Ruby on Rails, ExpressJS, JavaScript, and ReactJS. I bring 6 years of working as a Calibration Technician with strong skills in customer service, meeting deadlines, and building relationships. Two of those years being the website lead which let me explore my vision for design, as well as, application/database management. I have a love for learning and constantly challenge myself to master something new. As a developer, I'm excited to be in a collaborative environment and use my creativity and problem-solving skills to help a company create quality products.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Microsoft Office, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, ReactJS, NextJS, Sass, Tailwind CSS, Bootstrap, Framer Motion, Responsive Design, MySQL, PostgreSQL, Ruby on Rails, Git, NodeJS, ExpressJS, Seguelize, RESTful APIs, Object-Oriented Programming, JSON, jQuery, Google, Agile Development, Stack Overflow, Figma

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

QuizChamp - Live Demo | Front End Github | Back End Github

A quiz application that persists user data and scores. Application utilizes a leader board and crown reward system.

- Implemented with a ReactJS front end and a Express/NodeJS back end.
- Deployed MySQL database
- Ongoing live service application with new guizzes being added regularly.

EntSpot - Live Demo | Github

An IMDB clone using the TMDB expansive API. Search and find information and link to all forms of entertainment!

- Created with NextJS & Tailwind CSS responsive design.
- Features a light and dark mode.
- Operates smoothly with a clean and simple UI.
- Tailors experience for users on any screen type.

EXPERIENCE

Hocker, Inc. Houston, Texas 11/2016 - Present

Calibration Technician | Website Lead | Customer Support

- Oversee product management and price control on the company website.
- Conduct hardware troubleshooting and software debugging.
- Deliver on deadlines set by customers and manufacturers.

Customer Engineering Services (CES)

Houston, Texas

Technician | Trainer | Customer Support Specialist

04/2015 - 11/2016

- Trained 75+ employees on the use and maintenance of photo lab equipment and software.
- Provided on the spot debugging of software issues and hardware complications.
- Presented issues found with software with development teams to assist in rectifying errors.

EDUCATION

Flatiron School Houston, Texas Full Stack Software Engineering Ruby on Rails and JavaScript program 05/2021 - 03/2022

Lonestar Community College

Houston, Texas 08/2012 - 04/2014

Coursework completed towards a Bachelors Degree in Audio Engineering